LORENZO LÓPEZ-SANCHO ABRAHAM

lorenzo.lopez@intec.es (+44) - (0)7 831 678 944

SENIOR DEVELOPER / ARCHITECT

Profile

Software developer and architect. Specialist in J2EE and Ruby on Rails. Deep knowledge in development, databases and systems administration.

Skills

Development

I can develop in multiple languages but my specialty is Web Development using Java or Ruby and Rails.

Architecture/Design

Ample experience in the whole development lifecycle. My knowledge in UNIX sysems and databases allow me to design quick and responsive applications.

Agile

Experiencie working with agile teams, scrum, iterative development and pair programming.

Technical Knowledge

Development	Virtualization	Miscelánea
Core Java, Multithreading	VMWare: Workstation, ESX, VI	Scripting (UNIX and Powershell)
JSP, Struts2, JSF	VirtualBox, Chef	Microsoft Exchange
Spring, Hibernate, EJB	Databases	Business Objects
SOA, Webservices, JSON	SLQ Server, Oracle, DB2, Informix	Apache Tomcat, Weblogic
Javascript (Backbone, jQuery)	Teradata, OLAP, BI	Criptography and Security
Ruby on Rails	os	Project Management, Agile, ITIL
Sinatra, Grape	UNIX (Linux ,Solaris, AIX, OSX)	Matlab
Python	Windows Server (2003 and 2008)	Autocad

Experience

Lead Developer / Architect Tesco PLC

2012

As Ruby on Rails Lead Developer I currently mantain and develop web solutions for Tesco promotions team. As Architect currently engineering the move from web applications to a full SOA architecture using RoR and Sinatra. Right now I am developing applications using Sinatra/Grape and Backbone.

Freelance Trainer Multiple companies

2003-2012

Training multiple companies as El Corte Ingles, ONO, Telefónica, AstraZeneca, etc teaching different subjects as programming (Java, .NET, C), O.S (Windows Server, UNIX), Databases (Oracle, MySQL, Teradata, Informix, SQL Server) or BI (Business Objects, Matlab)

Software Developer Analist MTV Spain

2011

Developer of a reporting system using Crystal Reports and SQL Server. Automated flows of information between MTV and its subsidiaries using ruby on rails.

Java Architect / Trainer

2005-2012

Avante Formacion

Working as Java expert helping develop architectures and training different companies in Java Best Practices. Specializing in j2EE, Struts, Spring, JSF, Hibernate and Open ESB.

Ruby on Rails Software Developer Canary Lab

2011

Developed a website with every book published in Spain since year 1000 AD. The site was developed using Ruby on Rails, MySQL and Thinking Sphinx

Ruby on Rails Software Developer Intec Consulting SCM

2010

Development of the website tesis.com.es. It contains every thesis published in Spain since 1977. Developed using Ruby on Rails, MySQL and Thinking Sphinx.

OLAP Solutions Architect

2009-2010

Intec Consulting SCM

Definition and implementation of different OLAP systems using Teradata and SQL Server Analysis Services.

IT Director, Software Development Intec Consulting SCM

2003-2008

Led the IT department to use state of the art technologies to deliver high performance applications in a timely manner.

Project Manager UCMTA

2007

Development of a CMS for the european project e-emprendedoras.es for empowering women in the job market. The application was developed using Ruby on Rails and MySQL.

Ruby on Rails Software developer Intec Consulting SCM

2007

Development of the prospectos.org website. It contains every drug sold in Spain. The application has been developed using Ruby on Rails, MySQL and Thinking Sphinx.

Project Manager UCMTA

2006

Manager and developer for the European Project Aldebaran. Aldebaran is a document management software developed for the European Commission. It was developed using J2EE, Spring and Hibernate.

Acted as Project manager/Architect/Developer for the TOP Talent system in Hay Group. TOP Talent is a KPI based application for evaluation of managers in big companies (Like Vocento Group in Spain). I supervised the whole SDLC from architecture to deployment in Vocento Group servers. TOP Talent was developed in Java using XForms and deployed using Tomcat.

Software Developer Intec Consulting SCM

2006

Developed Intranet application for managing courses and teachers working for Intec SCM. The application was developed using Ruby on Rails, Ferret (Search engine) and MySQL

Java Software Developer

2003

Travelsoft / Soluziona

Developer of a jetspeed based portal for a travel retailer. It was a mix between a news systems and a CMS. Its main goal was being a portal for travel agencies. I was the main developer and helped in the deployment too. I came to the team as a Java lead developer to help them meet the deadlines.

Lead Architect

2000-2002

El Corte Ingles

Architecting the different solutions for internal applications in El Corte Ingles using Java. Acted as liaison between the different departments in El Corte Ingles and the developers and project managers. Developing proof of concepts and documentation. I also was in charge of security standards for java applications (Web and Desktop based)

UNIX Systems Manager

1998-2000

Universidad Autonoma de Madrid

Systems manager for all Linux computers inside university. Acted as liason between teachers and management to ensure classrooms where installed as required for the different courses. I defined the procedures for installing and updating the Linux computers and installed and configured all software

Education

Universidad Autónoma de Madrid (1993-1999)

Mathematics

Ecole polytechnique fédérale de Lausanne (2012)

Functional Programming Principles in Scala

Stanford University (2012)

Cryptography I

Georgia Tech (2012)

Computational Investing I

Languages

Spanish

Native level

English

High Level, written and spoken

German

Intermediate level

Lorenzo López-Sancho Abraham — lopez@intec.es — (+44) - 07 831 678 944